Welcome back. In this lesson,
we are going to dive into object oriented programming in Kotlin.
Let's refresh a bit of terminology,
so that we're all calling the same things by the same names.
Classes are blueprints for objects.
Like this is an aquarium blueprint.
Objects are instances of classes that is the actual aquarium.
Properties are characteristics of classes such as the length,
width, and height of an aquarium.
Methods are the functionality of the class,
what the object they could do for example, fill with water.
Interfaces are a specification that a class can implement.
For example, cleaning is common not just to aquariums,
and cleaning generally happens in similar ways.
So, we can have an interface clean,
and aquarium could implement it.
In the following screencast,
we're going to build some classes around our aquarium exploring all those concepts.