Hello. Let's define a class for our Aquarium.
For that, let's create a new package.
This is not required,
but it's always a good idea to keep our classes organized in packages.
On the source folder,
right-click and select ''New package'' and call it "Aquarium."
And then, create a new Kotlin File in the Aquarium package.
Right-click on ''Source'', select new Kotlin File/Class,
and also call it ''Aquarium. ''
Inside the file, we can define a class Aquarium
using the class keyword and the name of the class.
Class names by convention start with a capital letter.
This is a valid class in Kotlin and you don't see any errors in IntelliJ,
but it doesn't have or do anything.
Let's add curly braces so we can define something inside the class.
Let's define some properties or characteristics for the aquarium class.
Here are properties for the length, width, and height.
We're setting them in the class,
and currently they're val,
which makes them immutable.
Immutable means that they can't be modified after they're created.
So, all Aquariums we create will have the same size.
That' s not very interesting and we're going to fix it in a moment.
But first, let's create an instance.
We need a place to do that.
So let's create a file for
our main function and the other functions that are not methods.
Right-click on ''Aquarium'' and select ''new Kotlin File/Class,'' and call it ''Main.''
Inside the same file,
we create another main function, there it is.
We can have more than one main function,
and you can choose the one you're on by right-clicking on it and choosing ''Run.''
And from inside main,
we call a function ''buildAquarium'',
which gives an error until we implement the function.
So, we defined buildAquarium,
and now we don't have any more errors.
In buildAquarium, we create an Aquarium.
We do this by calling Aquarium as if it was a function.
This does the same thing that the new keyword does in other languages.
It creates a new instance of Aquarium by calling its constructor.
As the name implies,
constructors construct object instances from class descriptions.
We'll do more with constructors later.
Now, also in buildAquarium,
let's print out the values of the length, width, and height.
Notice that you can access the properties directly,
myAquarium.length, myAquarium.width and myAquarium.height.
Another hood, Kotlin actually made a getter for all three properties,
even though we didn't write any code.
When we access properties directly,
Kotlin always calls the corresponding getter,
even though it looks like they're accessing just the property.
When we run a program,
it prints the dimensions as expected.
Now to be able to change the values of the dimensions,
firstly, we make the dimensions changeable by using var,
instead of val in the aquarium class.
The difference between val and var is that variables
declared as val cannot be changed once they have been assigned a value,
and variables declared with var can be changed.
IntelliJ is really helpful here by underlining vars for us in the code.
Now in buildAquarium, we can make our Aquarium much taller and print out the new value.
Two things to notice here,
we don't have to change my Aquarium to a var,
because we're not changing the Aquarium,
it's the same object we are modifying its properties.
When talking about Aquariums,
usually, we talk about the amount of water that goes in.
So, our first inclination might be to create a method in the Aquarium class
that calculates and returns the volume of our fish tank in leaders, like so.
To take better advantage of Kotlin,
we can write this function which has only one line in
its body as a one-liner declaration, like so.
When we look at this,
really, we are just getting a value.
The fact that it's a function that
does calculation is not important to the person getting the value.
So, this is better represented as a property.
This property has a default getter that returns its value.
Since we want to calculate the value,
we can override the default getter to calculate the value.
The syntax is like this,
we declared a property and its type,
and then customarily on a new line,
we define the get function.
And we can write this in one line too.
Let's print the volume in buildAquarium.
We access this as a property,
but it is an expression,
so it needs curly braces.
Because under the hood,
this calls the get function.
Setters work in the same way.
Currently, volume is a val,
so it can't be set again.
Let's change this and make it a var,
and add a setter below the getter.
By convention, the name of the setter parameter is value,
but you can choose a different name if you prefer.
When we're given a new volume,
at least one of the dimensions of the Aquarium has to change.
Let's just change the height.
So, in our setter,
let's add code that takes the new value in litters,
and turns it into cubic centimeters,
and calculates the new height.
If you didn't want anyone outside the class to be able to use the setter,
you could make it private.
But we're going to leave it public for now.
Sean's now going to talk more about private and other visibility modifiers.
Did you notice that there are no visibility declarations in this program so far?
In Kotlin, everything is public by default.
That means all of your variables and clauses can be accessed everywhere,
even the member variables of an object.
There are visibility modifiers in Kotlin,
and you can use them to limit the size of the API that you expose.
At the package level,
if you do not specify any visibility modifier,
public is used by default.
Which means that your declarations will be visible everywhere.
The Main function and the buildAquarium function, are currently public.
If you mark a declaration private,
it will only be visible inside the file containing the declaration.
Since we're only going to use buildAquarium inside this file,
we can make it private.
If you mark buildAquarium internal,
it is visible anywhere in the same module.
A module is a set of Kotlin files compiled together.
When it's internal, we can use it from anywhere inside our project.
But, if we compile the library,
it wouldn't be exported as a function.
For members declared inside the class,
again by default, they are public.
Public means that any client who sees the class can also see it's public members.
Private means members are only visible inside the class.
Importantly, subclasses cannot see private members.
And protected means the same as private,
but members are also visible to subclasses.
And of course class members can have a visibility of internal as well.
It works just like internal at the file level.
That was a lot to take in.
You can learn more about visibility in the documentation linked in the notes.