Our Aquarium class would be much more
useful if we could specify the size when we create it.
We do this by passing in values.
As a first approach,
we can pass in values in the same way as function parameters and then,
assign them to the member variables.
Here are saying, make an aquarium constructor with three parameters;
length, width and height.
We're assigning the constructor arguments to properties length,
width and height inside the class body.
Just like with functions,
we can also use defaults.
While you can write it that way and it's good for spelling things out,
it's not good Kotlin.
We can simplify this code by declaring the variables with
the constructor like this and get rid of the assignments.
By using var or val on the constructor arguments,
it creates the member properties for you and
assigns the past in values or to default values.
This is a really common pattern in Kotlin
and the way most classes with constructors are declared.
Let's create a small 20 by 15 by 30 aquarium in our buildAquarium function.
To make this more readable,
let's pass in named parameters and print the volume for this small aquarium.
But what if we want to do more than assign
member variable values in the constructor when we create an object?
For example, when we feel an aquarium with water,
the water doesn't usually take up all of the tank.
Because it would overflow and spill really easily.
So, when we create the aquarium,
we can calculate the maximum amount of water to put in.
Let's create a changeable variable water and set it to
90% of the volume and because we multiply with 0.9,
the inferred data type is a double.
We need to put it below volume because properties
get initialized in the order in which they are defined.
Notice that we can use constructor parameters,
other properties or even member functions to initialize properties.
Finally, if we need to have another constructor than the default one for our class,
there is a way to do that.
For example, instead of specifying the dimensions when we create the aquarium,
we might want to specify the number of fish when we create an aquarium in buildAquarium.
This gives us an error until we define a matching constructor.
For our constructor, a constructor starts with the constructor keyword,
followed by arguments, a colon and a call to the default constructor with this.
Note that when we create an aquarium,
we can't mix constructor arguments.
So, we cannot create an aquarium passing the length and the number of fish.
The arguments have to match exactly with one of the available constructors.
Our errors are gone and now we can print our small aquarium in buildAquarium.
The dimensions have the default values because we are not doing
anything in the new constructor yet. Let's fix that.
We want our fish to have plenty of room,
so let's say we put one centimeter of fish per
two liters or 2000 cubic centimeters of water.
Inside the constructor, we do the calculations that are specific for this constructor.
We can now run our program and get an aquarium size based on the number of fish.
Shaun, anything else to say about constructors?
Thanks Alex.
I wanted to talk a bit more about constructors and a related concept in it.
I'll define a fish class to dive in further.
Let's do that in a new file called fish.
Fish has two parameters and here's the class declaration.
Friendly, is declared as a vowel,
so column will create a property for friendly.
We'll use that to note if a fish is friendly or aggressive.
Volume needed does not have val or var,
so Kotlin will not create a property from this argument for you.
This class declaration also results in Kotlin gradient constructor from this information.
In Kotlin, most classes only specify this one constructor
and with default parameters constructor overloading is not needed.
That is you don't have to define a constructor for each combination of arguments.
Now, to do something with volume needed,
let's define a vowel size of int on fish.
And then, in an init block,
calculate the size that object creation time.
Init works just like a constructor and that we
can put logic in it to initialize our properties.
If the fish is friendly,
it only needs the specified volume.
However, if the fish is aggressive,
it needs twice the minimum volume.
And if we make a function,
we can create a fish and print it out.
However, this gives an error because volume needed is not a property.
Here's the correct code where we use size instead.
When we run it, it prints the size of the fish.
Alex showed you how to declare secondary constructors.
Let's define one now in fish.
It's going to look like this.
In Kotlin, you typically don't need secondary constructors.
Most classes only provide a primary constructor,
but if you do declare a secondary constructor,
it must contain a call to the primary constructor by using this.
You also have to pass any required arguments.
Let's add some more init box to this class.
You can use init blocks the way you would use a constructor body in other languages.
You can have more than one in init block and they
always run before any secondary constructors.
And they can be almost anywhere in your class.
They're executed in order from the top of the class to the bottom.
So, if you were using any properties they need to come before the init blocks.
You don't have to explicitly call on it.
It's called as part of the constructor.
Now, in a lot of languages,
defining a lot of constructors is normal.
In Kotlin, you have default parameters.
Because of that, good Kotlin classes only define
one constructor with default parameters for optional values.
Now, if you would make a secondary instructor,
consider making a helper method instead.
Like this one, makeDefaultFish,
which only creates a friendly fish of size 50.
This keeps your classes simple while providing a clean API.
That was a lot about constructors.
Kotlin allows you a lot of flexibility with constructors,
but honestly, you can just keep it simple.
To write good Kotlin code,
just use one primary constructor and init blocks.
When you need more flexibility,
consider adding helper functions like make default fish.