Inheritance in Kotlin works pretty much as you'd expect,
if you've used a class-based language before.
But, there are some differences.
Let's say we want to have a different type of aquarium such as a cylindrical tower.
Tower tanks are a lot like regular aquariums,
but they are also different in some ways.
So,we couldn't inherit a lot of stuff from our basic aquarium,
and change to things that are different.
Let's do that in Kotlin.
Here is our original aquarium class.
It doesn't say explicitly,
but this class actually inherits from the top level class 'Any'.
You could add colon 'Any' to the declaration.
But, it's not required and doesn't give you anything extra.
The first thing we have to do to be able to inherit from a class,
is make the class open.
By default, classes are not subclassible.
We have to explicitly allow it.
Now, in the same file is ok,
we can create a class tower tank that inherits from aquarium.
We specify the inheritance or the parent class, after the colon.
We need to change how the volume is
calculated and we don't want to fill as much water into the tall tank.
We are doing this by overriding the water property in tower tank.
We also need to override the get function for the volume.
We're going to need to multiply by pi,
which we input from
the math library and then
convert the result to an integer because the water is an integer.
This leaves us with errors.
It's because, just like classes,
members are not available for subclassing by default.
This is so we don't accidentally leak implementation details without meaning to.
So, let's make water and volume open,
and all the errors are gone.