Different types of fish have lots in common,
and they do similar things,
in somewhat different ways.
For example, all fish have a color,
and all fish have to eat.
So, we want to make sure that all our fish that we create do that.
Kotlin offers two ways of doing that.
One is abstract classes,
and one is interfaces.
Both are classes that cannot be instantiated on their own,
which means you cannot create objects of those types yet.
The difference is that abstract classes have
constructors while Interfaces can't have any constructor logic.
In aquarium fish, let's make a very simple abstract class.
Aquarium fish; abstract classes start with the abstract keyword.
Because aquarium fish is abstract,
we can't make instances of aquarium fish directly.
We need to provide sub classes that implement its missing functionality.
Let's create two sub classes;
shark and plecostomus, and make them inherit from aquarium fish.
This leaves us with errors,
because we have to implement the abstract property color.
So let's add, that sharks are of color gray,
and plecos are of color gold.
And then, we can use it like any other class.
Let's add a function,
make fish to the main file.
This function creates a shark and a pleco,
and prints out their colors.
Let's call it in main.
When we run it with all the other stuff,
we get the new fish and they print their color.
Next, in aquarium fish,
let's add an interface,
fish action, that defines an eat function.
Let's update our sharks and pleco classes.
Add a comma, and then the fish action interface.
Implement eat.
Here are the finished classes.
Add code to make fish,
to make the fish eat.
A final thing that you can do in Kotlin,
when using classes that implement interfaces,
is create objects where you specify that
the only thing you can do with them is what's defined in the interface.
Let's say, we want to make a function ''feed fish'',
and when a fish gets the food, it eats it.
We don't care what kind of fish it is,
as long as it can eat the food.
''Eat'' is defined in fish action,
so every fish we passed to feed fish,
needs to implement fish action.
We don't care about any other properties.
As long as it implements fish action, we can use it.
We can specify that with our function parameter,
by making it of tide fish action.
Now, only fish that implement fish action can be passed into ''feed fish''.
Now, this is a simplistic example,
but when you have a lot of classes,
this can help you keep clearer and more organized.
So, Sean is going to talk more about,
what is the difference between abstract classes,
and interfaces, and how to use them right.
Thanks, Alex. There's really
only one syntax difference in Kotlin between abstract classes and interfaces.
Abstract classes can have constructors and interfaces cannot.
Both interfaces and abstract classes can contain implementations of methods.
On interfaces, we call them default implementations.
The big difference really is in when and how you use them.
Use an interface if you have a lot of methods
and one or two default implementations, like this.
Use an abstract class anytime you can't complete a class.
For example, going back to our aquarium fish,
and making all aquarium fish implement fish action,
we can provide a default implementation for ''eat'' while leaving color abstract.
That's because there isn't really a good default color for a fish.
But really, column provides us a better tool for this than abstract classes.
Interface delegation;
interface delegation let's you add features to a class via composition.
Composition is when you use an instance of
another class as opposed to inheriting from it.
Instead of requiring the caller's subclass,
a giant abstract class,
give them a small interface,
and let them delegate those interfaces to an object.
This sounds pretty abstract.
How do we do composition?
Let's define a new main function, to explore composition,
and implement delegate to create a plecostomus and print its color and food.
Let's start by breaking up aquarium fish into interfaces.
Fish action, and fish color;
fish action will let us eat,
and fish color will give our fish a color.
Now, update plecostomus, to implement both the fish action,
and fish color interfaces.
We can remove inheritance from aquarium fish
because we get all the functionality from the interfaces,
and we don't even have to change the code in the body of plecostomus.
Next, let's use interface delegation to provide a color implementation.
To do that, we need an object that knows how to provide a fish color.
Let's make a basic object called gold color that implements fish color.
All it does is say that its color is gold.
It doesn't really make sense to make multiple instances of
gold color as they would all do the exact same thing.
Kotlin let's us declare a class where we can only have
one instance by using the keyword ''object'' instead of ''class''.
This will declare a class and make exactly one instance of it.
The instance will be called gold color and there's
no way to make another instance of this class but that's okay,
we don't need to.
If you're familiar with the Singleton pattern,
this is how to implement it in Kotlin.
We're all set to use interface delegation now.
Back on our plecostomus,
we say ''buy gold color'' next to fish color,
and we remove the member variable.
This means implement the interface fish color
by deferring all calls to the object, gold color.
So every time you call the color property on this class,
it will actually call the color property on gold color, pretty neat, huh?
Of course there are different colors of plecostomi in the world.
So, we can make the fish color object
a constructor parameter with a default value of gold color,
and defer calls to the color property to whatever fish color we get passed in.
So, for example, if we were passed in a red color,
then fish color would be by red color and return red.
Let's do one more example of this.
All our eat methods,
so far, have just print out the food.
So, we can make a printing fish action.
It takes a food as a parameter and implements fish action.
We override eat, and instead of printing a fixed string,
we print out whatever food we were passed.
Since we have a member variable food,
we can't make printing fish action an object.
We want a different instance for each food that we pass in.
An then in plecostomus,
we can replace the overrided E with the delegation to fish action.
And we don't need the curly braces anymore either.
Now, our plecostumus doesn't have a body.
All its overrides are handled by interface delegation.
Here is the running code.
Interface delegation is really powerful,
and you should generally consider how to use it whenever you
might use an abstract class in another language.
It let's you use composition to plug-in behaviors.
Instead of requiring a lot of sub classes,
each specialized in a different way.