It's getting crowded, so we are going to put
the code for this segment into a new package under
aquarium and call it decorations and a new file also called decorations.
Now, let's add a main function and a makeDecorations function.
Often, we have classes that mostly act as data containers.
In Kotlin, for classes that mostly hold data,
there is a data class with benefits.
Recreate data classes by prefixing arc decoration with data.
We can for example,
create a class decorations that knows about aquarium decorations.
You can then create an instance of this class in
makeDecorations and print all its properties.
Let's run, just decorations,
with a data class printing the object,
prints the values of properties,
instead of just an address of the object,
that is the object pointer.
Basically, it creates toString for us to print the properties.
Let's create two more decorations in makeDecorations,
d2 with slate and d3, also with slate.
The data class also provides an equals method to compare two instances of a data class.
Let's add two print statements that compare d1 to d2 and d2 to d3.
Let's run our code.
In the result, when we compare granite and slate,
we get false and when we compare slate to slate, we get true.
You can copy data objects,
using the copy method.
This creates a new object with the same property values,
so when you print it they are the same.
Let's make a data class with some more decorations,
we call it decorations2 and add wood and a diver and create another decoration with it.
To get at the properties and assign them to variables,
Kotlin, let's us use a process called decomposition.
We can make three variables,
one for each property and assign the object to it.
Kotlin puts the property value in each variable and we can then use it.
You do need to put parentheses around the variables for decomposition.
The number of variables must match the number of properties or you get
a compiler error and
the variables are assigned in the order in which they are declared in the class.