There are three other types of special purpose classes you can make with Kotlin.
The first special type of class where Kotlin removes
boilerplate acrobatics from your code singletons.
For example, there can only be one MobyDickWhale.
To create a singleton,
use the object keyword when you declare your class, and that's it.
Anytime you're defining a class that shouldn't be instantiated multiple times,
you can use the object keyword in place of class.
When you do that, Kotlin will instantiate exactly one instance of the class.
In this example, MobyDickWhale is an object,
and there can only be one MobyDick.
So, we declare it as an object instead of a class.
Kotlin also has enums,
which let you enumerate items.
Here, we're declaring an enum with red,
green, and blue colors.
Enums actually define a class and you can give them properties or even methods.
You declare an enum by modifying the class keyword with enum.
Enums are like the MobyDick object.
Kotlin will make exactly one red,
exactly one green, and exactly one blue.
There's no way to create more than one color object.
There's not any way to define more colors,
other than where the enum is declared.
The last type of class in Kotlin is a sealed class.
A sealed class is special.
It's a class that can be subclassed,
but only inside the file which it's declared.
If you try to subclass it in a different file, you'll get an error.
Because the class and subclasses are in the same file,
Kotlin will be able to know all subclasses statically,
that is at compile time.
The compiler can see all of the classes and
subclasses and it knows these are all of them.
So, the compiler can do extra checks for you.
This makes sealed classes a safe way to represent a fixed number of types.
They're great for returning success or err from a network API, for example.
Let's declare a sealed class.
Staying with the fish theme,
I'll call this class seal.
Seals are not actually fish,
but they do eat fish.
Now, I can make two subclasses,
sea lion and walrus,
they're both types of seals.
If I wanted to add more seals,
I have to put them in this file.
I can't sub-class seal in any other file.
Since they're all in the same file,
Kotlin knows statically about all of the subclasses.
I can use a when statement to check what type of seal I have.
If I don't match all of the types of seal,
Kotlin will give me a compiler error.