Wow, this was a hefty class.
Let's get up and do some stretches.
I wonder, do fish do stretches?
What kind of stretches do you think fish would do?
So, in this lesson,
we learned Kotlin's way of doing object-oriented programming with classes,
abstract classes, and interfaces,
and we added bits and pieces to your aquarium.
I think the best thing you can do for yourself after this lesson is practice.
Have some fun, write some code,
whether it's turning this example into coherent program,
or writing that game you've been putting off,
and then come back for the next lesson where we'll have
a whole basket of Kotlin goodness for you, including-
Constants, collections, and generics.