Welcome to lesson five;
the final lesson of this course.
This lesson is all about fish because for most people,
the main attraction of an aquarium are its fish.
So, how about we try our hands at picking and breeding some fish?
So, we'll also do a little bit of Kotlin on the side.
We'll revisit Lambdas and go a little deeper because they
are one of the essential specialities of Kotlin.
This leads to higher order functions,
basically functions that take functions as arguments.
This makes Kotlin extremely flexible.
We'll talk about SAM or single abstract methods,
as well as inline.
I'm looking forward to finding out more about SAM.
If they have an aquarium, I'm all for it.
To close out, we'll play with filters;
the Kotlin type not the aquarium type.
We'll talk a little bit about the standard library,
and where you can go if you want to study more fish.
Kotlin.