To follow along from a clean slate,
start a new package with a new file for this lesson.
I am calling them both Aquarium5.
Create a fish data class with one property for the name.
Add a name function that calls fishExamples.
Then, add fishExamples and in fishExamples,
create a variable fish with a name,
let's call it splashy.
Writing higher-order functions with extension
lambdas is the most advanced part of the Kotlin language.
It takes a while to learn how to write them.
However, they are really convenient to use.
Let's make a simple one to see how this works.
We used with in a previous lesson to apply several operations to an object.
It looks like this, inside fishExample,
we can call with with an object.
Then, inside the lambda,
between the curly braces,
the object is implicitly referenced by the word this.
Here we're saying, with fish name, call this.capitalize.
We don't actually need the this because it's implicit,
so let's remove it.
Under the hood, with is a higher order function.
To see how this works,
we can make our own greatly simplified version of with that just works for strings.
To get started, we need to define a function,
myWith that takes two arguments.
The arguments will be the object on which to execute the operation
and a function that defines the operation to execute on the object.
So for our example,
we create a function, myWith.
It takes a string object,
we'll call it name because we want to pass in the name of the fish.
The second argument is the function definition for the operation.
Block is the name of the function.
The function needs a name so we can use it in the body of the myWith function.
We can call the function anything we want but by convention it's called block.
Next, comes a colon.
After the colon, we specify the class we are extending,
so that we can use myWith on it.
We want to use myWith on a string,
so we need to extend the string class.
The class we are extending is often called the receiver object.
Finally, we specify the return type of the function argument,
which in this case is unit,
since we are not returning anything.
So, locally, inside the function body of myWith,
block is now an extension function on a string object and we can apply it to a string.
So, we can apply the parsed in function to the parsed in argument.
We take name and call block on it.
Now, in fish example,
instead of with, we can replace with with myWith.
Fish.name is our name argument and capitalize is
our block function and so we are applying capitalized to splashy.
Capitalize returns a copy of the past in string,
it does not change the original string.
So, to see that this is actually happening,
we can wrap our curl to capitalize into a print statement.
When we execute the code,
it prints splashy with a capital s.
Now, with is already provided for us in the standard library and it is just one example.
There are tons of built in functions in
the Kotlin standard library that use extension lambdas.
Here is a handful that you'll find useful.
Run is an extension that works with all data types.
It takes one lambda as its argument and returns the result of executing the lambda.
In this example, run will just return the name of the fish.
Apply is similar to run and can also be used on all data types.
But unlike run which returns the result of the block function,
apply returns the object it's applied to.
So, if we apply it to fish,
it'll return the fish object.
It turns out that apply can be really useful for
calling functions on a newly created object.
Here is an example of using apply.
We create a new fish and before we assign it to a variable, we call apply.
Then, we apply a lambda to set its name.
So, the difference is that run returns the result of executing
the lambda while apply returns the object after the lambda has been applied.
So, apply returns the fish that we just constructed.
This is a really common pattern for initializing objects.
Now, there is also let.
Let returns a copy of the changed object.
Let is particularly useful for chaining manipulations together.
Here is an example where we first capitalize fish.
Then, add another string to it.
Then, get its length at 31 and print the result.
You'll find yourself using these functions everywhere in your Kotlin code