Kotlin provides a very powerful construct when
working with higher order functions, Inline.
Let's continue with our example function, myWith.
It takes a string name and an extension, Lambda.
In the body, it applies the extension,
Lambda to the name,
and we call it like this.
Here, we're saying call myWith on fish.name,
and we're parsing it a Lambda which we'll call capitalize on the name.
There's one problem with this.
Every time we call myWith,
Kotlin will make a new Lambda object.
Yes, Lambdas are objects.
A Lambda expression is an instance of a function interface,
which is itself a subtype of object.
To help understand, we can write it out longhand like this.
Creating an instance of function one every time myWith is called,
takes CPU time and memory.
This isn't a problem most of the time,
but if we're defining something like myWith that we'll
use everywhere or the Lambda is more complex,
the overhead, that is the required resources, can add up.
To fix this problem,
Kotlin let's us define myWith as inLine.
That is a promise that every time myWith is called,
it will actually transform the source code to inLine, the function.
That is, the compiler will change the code to
replace the Lambda with the instructions inside the Lambda.
That means zero overhead.
Let's look at how. When the inLine transform is applied,
the call to the Lambda is replaced with the contents of the function body of the Lambda.
In our myWith example,
when we apply the transform,
capitalize is called directly on fish.name.
This is really important.
Kotlin let's us define Lambda-based APIs with zero overhead.
It won't even pay the cost of calling the function myWith since it gets inlined.
It's worth noting, inlining large functions does increase
your code size so it's best used for simple functions like myWith.
As a user of these APIs,
we don't have to worry about creating extra objects;
the compiler will take care of it for us.