It's time to introduce SAM.
If you've never heard of SAM, no worries.
We will introduce them now.
SAM is an acronym for Single Abstract Method.
You'll run into SAM all the time in APIs written in the Java programming language.
Runnable and callable are two examples.
Basically, SAM just means an interface with one method on it. That's it.
In this example, runnable has an abstract method,
"run", and callable has a single method, "call".
In Kotlin, we have to call functions that take SAM as parameters all the time.
Here, we can make a function in the Java programming language.
Run now as an example of a function that takes
a runnable interface as a parameter and executes the run method.
If we want to call run now,
we can make an object of runnable and implement the run method.
This syntax object: class let's you instantiate an object that implements an interface.
It's useful for passing parameters like this,
not too exciting, but that's a lot of code just to call println.
Fortunately, in Kotlin, we can pass a lambda in place of a SAM.
Kotlin will take care of making the right kind of object for us.
This is really nice.
Even cooler if you take the SAM as the last parameter like we do here.
You can use the last parameter call syntax to specify the lambda outside of the prints.
And that's all I've got to say about SAM.
Writing your own extensions and higher-order functions is a lot of fun.
However, we've mentioned the Standard Library many times throughout this course.
Before you write your own,
always check the Standard Library to see if someone has saved you some work.
Studying the Standard Library is also a great way of finding out all of
the many features of Kotlin that we did not have time to touch in this course,
and new functionality is added frequently.
In the notes below is a link for all of the packages,
extensions, and utilities of the Standard Library.