This function has all the basic parts of a Kotlin function.
It starts with the keyword "fun."
Then, comes the name of the function,
printHello, followed by parentheses for arguments.
But we don't have any arguments and
the function body where things happen inside the curly braces.
And we execute the function by invoking its name followed by the parentheses.
If instead of using the interpreter,
we want to write and save a program in IntelliJ,
we have the following steps.
In the left-hand navigation,
there is a list of all our project files and folders.
Find and right-click the source folder.
Select new Kotlin File Class,
name the file "AMS" and click ''OK''.
The file is now in your source folder,
and it's extension is.kt.
We can now put our code into this file and eventually execute it.
We'll also use the repl and switch back and forth as it's convenient.
Firstly, to run an actual Kotlin program,
we need a main function.
Main is always the entry point for execution.
In Kotlin, it looks like this.
It's called Main.
It takes an array of strings as
its arguments followed by the function body in curly braces,
and we print "Hello World."
This function has no return statement,
but every function in Kotlin returns something even when nothing is explicitly specified.
So, a function like main returns a type unit which is Kotlin's way of saying no value.
And when a function returns unit,
you don't have to specify it explicitly.
This is different from other languages where you have to
explicitly say you are returning nothing.
To run this function,
click on the green triangle next to the main function and select Run AMSKt.
IntelliJ will take a moment to build,
and execute the code,
and then you can see the result in the log window that opens.