To demonstrate how to run main with arguments,
we can pass to maine whom to say hello to.
Select Run, Edit Configurations,
type Kotlin for the program arguments,
and close the configurations window.
Then, change your code to use the argument.
Replace world with a dollar sign to start a string template.
In a string template,
instead of a string,
you put instructions for how to get a string,
either from a variable,
or from an expression.
The current value of the expression after the dollar sign will be inserted for printing.
In this example, it should be the value of the zeros argument to main,
args[0], which is Kotlin.
So, we get the value of args[0],
and put it inside curly braces.
We need to put args[0] inside curly braces,
because it's not a value.
Fetching the first element in the array is an expression.
Some other languages have statements,
which are lines of code that don't have a value.
In Kotlin, almost everything has a value,
even if that value is unit.
In programming language lingo,
we say that everything in Kotlin is an expression.
This is really cool, because it means for example,
you can use the value of an 'if' expression right away.
No need to make an extra variable to figure out which branch was taken.
So, for example we can assign an 'if' statement to a variable,
or even use it as a string template.
Here, we're checking the temperature to say a fish is
fried or safe based on the temperature,
and if we print that out, we'll see the fish is safe.