Now, that you've made a file with a main function,
it's time to define some more functions.
Let's add a function for our AMS that feeds the fish different foods on different days.
So, let's define a function,
feeds the fish that will hold our AMS logic and call it from main.
Let's make feed the fish to something.
Our goal is to pick a random day of the week and output a different food for each day.
We'll build it one step at a time.
First, let's put the basic structure together.
Inside the body of the feed the fish function,
add a variable called "day" and assign it to "Tuesday".
To start with, our AMS will only know about Tuesday.
Add a second variable called food that is pellet's.
That's what fish eat on Tuesdays.
Lastly, add a print statement using a string template.
This will print out today and food.
Let's run our program again and you'll see the output,
today is Tuesday and the fish eat pellet's.
Extending our functionality, we want to select
a random day of the week each time this program is run.
Below feed the fish,
create a function called random day with no arguments and it returns a string.
We are using strings for the weekdays in this example because it's
more readable and the final destination is to print the value.
Inside the function, create a list of weekdays as strings.
Below that, returned a value at a randomly chosen index inside the list.
Random gives us an error because we have to import the library.
Here are some things to notice about this finished function.
You are importing a Java library for random because under the hood,
Kotlin works seamlessly with Java libraries.
In the return statement,
we get a random number between zero and six.
Seven is the boundary and excluded.
And then, we return the associated weekday.
In feed the fish,
replace Tuesday with a call to random day.
When we run the program again a couple of times,
we see a random day of the week in the output.