Now, let's serve the fish a different food each day of the week.
We'll make another function for that,
and call it fish food.
Let's call fish food from feed the fish.
Since fish food will return a different food for each day of the week,
we need to parse the day as a parameter.
Now, let's define fish food.
A parameter is specified by its name,
a colon followed by the type.
Then we have the colon and the return type.
So, fish food takes a day as a parameter,
and it will return a string.
Here is the first version of the function body,
where we choose and return the food.
The when statement looks at the day variable,
and picks the correct food.
Note that you don't have a break at the end of the when branch.
When works a lot like case statements,
but it automatically breaks,
saving you from writing boilerplate code or writing accidental bugs.
But we can do much better.
Since everything in Kotlin has a value,
the when expression also has a value.
This value will be the last expression of the branch that was picked.
So, we can return the when value
directly without needing to assign the result to a variable.
When we do that, we must have an else branch to cover all cases.
The else case is the catch-all,
if none of the other branches matched.
To make sure the else case happens sometimes,
let's remove Tuesday and Saturday.
Now, we can run the code and see how it outputs the different days,
and foods, and fasting for the missing days.