Parameters in Kotlin can have a default value.
This means, when you call the function,
you don't have to specify a value every time for those parameters.
If the value is missing,
the default value is used.
Let's define a function swim with an argument speed that has a default value of fast.
By default, the fish will swim fast.
If we call swim with no arguments like this,
the default, fast, will be used.
We can also call the function and specify the default, argument,
positionally, or we can specify the argument by name like this.
You can mix default and positional arguments.
For example, we can let the fish swim for a time,
which doesn't have a default value,
and a speed, that does have a default value.
Our product manager just walked by and
mentioned that we're going to need to implement the ability to change the water.
Reading through the requirements doc,
sometime in the future,
we're going to build a temperature and dirtiness sensor.
In the meantime, we can use default values to fill in for the missing sensors.
Here is the function,
which doesn't do anything yet.
Day is a string.
Temperature gets a default value of 22 Celsius.
And dirty has a default value of 20 percent,
which is pretty clean.
There are three ways in which we can call this function.
We can call the function with three arguments in the right order.
We can call the function with
only the required arguments and use the default values for temperature and dirty.
And we can set only one or any of the values by specifying the name of the argument.
This is often more readable when calling functions with large numbers of arguments.
You can define a function where
the default variables are listed first or mixed in with others,
but this easily leads to mistakes if you forget to list all arguments by name.
Calling should change water.
With just Monday, gives the compiler error.
So, you have to call it,
specifying that Monday is the day.
It is a best practice to put arguments without defaults
first and then the ones with the defaults afterwards.
Should change water needs to return something?
For now, let's just have it return true.
Finally, we go back to our feed the fish function and add a call to should change water.
This code says that if we should change the water on a given day,
print, "Change the water today".
When we run the program,
we see "Change the water today" every time,
since we haven't implemented any logic for that,
which brings us to the next practice.