Welcome back.
I filled int with ChangeWater using a when statement value [inaudible].
I'm using a when statement here without a parameter for the when.
This works because with no parameter,
when acts as a sequence of if-else if checks.
This code reads, when temperature is greater than 30, return true.
Else, if dirty is greater than 30, return true.
Else, if it's Sunday,
return true, and else, return false.
This shouldChangeWater function works correctly,
but there is a lot of logic built into this when statement.
In Kotlin, you can do most things in
more than one way and some of those ways are unique to Kotlin.
So, let's see how we can improve or Kotlinize this function.
Another way we could write this function is to specify variables that
provide a name for each logic test at the beginning of the function body.
Let's give them a good name that indicates what we are testing.
Then assign the result of the tests to the variables,
isTooHot has the value of temperature larger than 30,
isDirty gets the result of testing Dirty,
and isSunday gets the result of that test.
Then in the when statement,
we can use the variables which makes it read like a list of statements.
We can use the same ideas to create functions in a single line.
For isTooHot, turn it into a function using
the fun keyword and passing the temperature as an argument.
We specify Boolean as the return type followed by
an equal sign and a one-line function body to check the temperature.
Because the return type can be inferred from the function,
we don't need it here.
The name of the function gives a hint to the reader about the expected return value.
You can declare functions this way whenever they have a single expression in their body.
Here is the code for isDirty and here is the code for isSunday.
Now, we can call these functions with an argument in the when statement.
Using this one-line function syntax,
you can simplify helper functions.
So it's a good idea to use them liberally in your code base.
If we run the program again,
it should output check the water every Sunday and randomly on other days.
One cool thing you can do with what we've just learned about functions is that
instead of assigning a fixed value as the default parameter,
you can assign a function whose return value becomes the default parameter.
Let's say that in the meantime,
our hardware team has built the first prototype of the dirty sensor.
We can define a function getDirtySensorReading that returns the sensor reading.
Now of course, this prototype only returns 20.
But they've promised us that the next version will support values all the way up to 42.
We can still set the value when we call the function.
That way, when the hardware team ships the new sensor,
they can just pass in the new one to replace our default argument.
Sometimes, you might be tempted to use
expensive functions to initialize default parameters.
Examples of expensive operations include reading files or allocating a lot of memory.
Be careful with this. They can affect the performance of your code quite a bit
because default parameters are evaluated at call time by Kotlin.
Here's an example of a function with an expensive default argument.
They can slow your app and has the potential for out-of-memory errors.
When called, you can pass in an existing aquarium but if you don't,
by default, it builds an entirely new aquarium which obviously takes a long time.
So, every time you call
aquariumStatusReport without passing a value for the aquarium argument,
a new aquarium will be made.
As a result, the report will probably take longer to produce,
be wrong most of the time,
and if you ask for a lot of reports,
the program will run out of memory and crash.
Did you notice the Any type for aquarium?
We're going to talk about that in the next lesson,
but for now, it's worth noting Any can hold any type of object.
For this section, we've done all of our control-flow logic using when statements.
But remember that Kotlin also comes with
all the basic structural programming operators that you're used to.
We saw if-else and for loops in lesson one and you can use while statements also.
In addition to these basic control flow operators,
you can find several control flow-like functions in the standard library, such as repeat.
The Kotlin standard library provides living essentials for
everyday work with Kotlin and we'll talk about it more in lesson five.
I do want to mention quickly,
while almost everything in Kotlin is an expression with a value,
there are a few exceptions.
There's no sensible value for while loops or for loops,
so they don't have any value.
If you try to assign a for loop to a variable,
you'll get an error saying it's a statement.
There are few other statements in Kotlin,
but honestly, you won't notice them during normal programming.
You can find the grammar on kotlinlang.org if you want to dig in more.