Filters are another control flow construct you can use from the standard library,
and you can do a lot of cool stuff with them.
We are just going to use a filter to pick some aquarium decorations.
Let's open ripple for this.
Ripple is very handy when you want to quickly try out some code snippet.
Say, we have a list of declarations.
To print all the decorations that start with the letter P,
we can filter the decorations and return a list
of the list elements that match the condition under filter.
To do this, we will call filter on the object.
Let's first see how a filter works.
Filter will test every decoration against its condition and return a Boolean.
So, if we return true,
all the elements get printed.
Inside the filter, you have the code that does the filtering.
It's in curly braces because we are evaluating
an expression for every element in decorations.
It refers to each element in the list on which we are calling the filter.
And we are testing whether the first character at position zero is equal to P. In Kotlin,
single quotes designate characters and double-quotes strings,
and they are not interchangeable like in some other languages.
Filters are powerful and we'll get more into filters later.
Filter, is a standard library function on list in Kotlin.
If you have some experience with filter in other languages,
you'll be wondering if it's eager or lazy,
and the answer is both.
I'm going to define a new function here example to explore this further.
By default, filter analyst is eager.
That means every time you call filter,
it creates a new list with the elements that pass through the filter.
So, for example, our variable eager here we'll hold a new list
containing the decorations that start with P. If you want lazy behavior in Kotlin,
you can use sequences.
A sequence is a collection that can only look at one item at a time,
starting at the beginning and going to the end.
Conveniently, this is exactly the API filter needs.
When you return the filter results as a sequence,
our filtered variable won't hold a new list,
it'll hold a sequence of all of the list elements
and knowledge of the filter to apply to its elements.
Whenever you access elements of the sequence,
the filter is applied and the results are returned to you.
Of course, if we want to turn our sequence back into the list,
we can call two list.
At that point, a filter will be run and all of
the values that start with P will be put in the new list.
To really visualize what lazy sequences are,
let's use the function map and tell it to print every item.
Since it's lazy, calling map doesn't print anything.
When I take the first element however,
you can see that the map operation reads the first value,
and of course, taking the full list will iterate over all the values.