So far, we've looked at named function declarations.
That is, each function has a name.
They look similar to functions in almost every programming language.
There's a fun keyword that says,
I'm about to declare a function.
It's followed by a name literal,
in this case swim,
that will never change.
Finally, it has a function body that says what to do when calling it.
This is all pretty basic stuff.
Kotlin also supports lambdas,
in other languages these are called anonymous
functions or function literals or similar names.
In Kotlin we call them Lambdas.
A Lambda is an expression that makes a function.
Instead of declaring a named function,
we declare a function that has no name.
Let's define a function with no name in REPL,
just to see the syntax.
A lambda is always surrounded by curly brackets in
Kotlin and since it's a function we can call it.
Of course, making a lambda and not doing anything with it isn't very useful.
Let's see what else we can do,
we can declare a variable called swim and assign it to a lambda.
Once we do that, we can call it just like a regular function,
by calling swim parents.
Lambdas can take arguments just like named functions.
Lambda arguments go on the left hand side of what's called a function arrow.
The body of the lambda goes after the function arrow.
So, this lambda function takes an int value as
an argument and returns the result of dividing it by two.
Closely related to lambda's is Kotlin syntax for function types.
You can use this syntax to clean we declare a variable,
that will hold the function.
In this case, we're saying make a variable waterFilter,
waterFilter can be any function that takes an int and returns an int.
Then we assign it to a lambda,
then note that we don't have to specify the type of the lambda argument anymore,
it's calculated by type inference.
Finally, return the value of dirty divided by two.
Of course, our fish make the aquarium dirty when they eat.
Let's make a similar function feedFish that makes the tank dirtier.
So far, we've just been using lambda to declare functions in a kind of weird way.
The real power of lambda happens when we make higher-order functions.
A higher-order function is really
just any function that takes a function as the argument.
Let's make one now,
updateDirty takes two parameters.
The first parameter is just an int and the second parameter is a function of int to int.
Finally, in the body of updateDirty we'll
just call the function we were past and return its value.
Note that operation has a function type just like we were using on
the variables and it's also important that operation is the last parameter.
Kotlin prefers function arguments to be the last parameter.
Now, our aquarium management system needs a dirty processor.
So, we'll make a new function and call it from feedTheFish.
Filling in dirty processor,
we can call updateDirty exactly like you'd expect, parsing waterFilter directly.
Now, let's parse feedFish to UpdateDirty.
Since feedFish is a name function and not a lambda,
you'll need to use a double colon to parse it.
This way Kotlin knows you're not trying to call feedFish,
and it let you parse a reference.
When you combine higher-order functions with lambdas,
Kotlin has a special syntax,
it's called the last parameter called syntax.
Here we call updateDirty again,
but this time we parse a lambda as an argument for the parameter operation.
What's really interesting here,
a lambda is an argument to updateDirty,
but since we're parsing it as the last parameter,
we don't have to put it inside the function parentheses.
To really show you what's going on,
you can put the parents back in.
Here you can see we're just parsing the lambda as an argument updateDirty.
Using this syntax, we can define
functions that look like they're built-in to the language.
Actually, you've already used a few higher-order functions from the standard library.
The filter function we used in the last section
takes a lambda and uses it to filter a list.
Repeat is also just a function.
Is defined in the standard library and it
takes a repeat count and a lambda that is repeated.