This last example shows one of the challenges,
and features of Kotlin.
You can do most things in more than one way, correctly.
And you can often compact code significantly.
Sometimes that helps readability,
and even performance, and sometimes it doesn't.
Finding the most compact,
or most readable version can be like a puzzle.
Because I'm still learning,
this means that I often write code in the easiest, almost familiar way,
and then I will play with it, changing it,
like a Rubik's Cube,
until I find the best way for what I want to accomplish.
I did say play because sometimes I really get into it, and it's fun.
So, have fun practicing,
and we'll see you for the next lesson,
where we'll look at classes.