You are more than halfway and in good shape to build
your very own aquarium with happy, healthy fish.
Don't forget, this course is, first and foremost,
about Kotlin, not aquarium care.
But there are so many more topics to cover,
and we don't have time to get deep into each of them.
Like you can create
a much better environment for your fish if you test the water quality regularly.
But what if your fish gets sick even if you do change the water?
How do you know what symptoms go with which disease,
and how do you treat it?
Does it matter what you feed your fish?
Can fish get vitamin deficiency or depression?
Do they have feelings?
Yes. Yes. That's a lot to learn,
and there's so much more Kotlin, too.
But this is a bootcamp about how to get you rolling with Kotlin,
so you are ready for other courses that use Kotlin to do cool things.
For example, with phones.
So, what we can do is give you starting points,
and that's what we're going to do in this lesson.
We're going to kick you off on
nine different topics and set you free to continue exploring on your own.
Among other things, we're going to cover pairs and more on collections,
show you how to do constants in Kotlin,
sneak a peek at annotations,
dive deep into generics,
and the most scary one, label breaks.
Generics is an advanced topic but super relevant for Kotlin,
and we'll walk you through it one step at a time.
And in the end, our fish will live in a perfect water supply.