Pairs are a neat Kotlin datatype that allows us to define a generic pair of values.
For example, we can associate
each piece of equipment with a description of what it's good for.
We define a variable for equipment,
and set it to a pair,
where the first item 'fishnet' is mapped to the second item 'catching fish'.
To access the first and second elements of this pair,
refer to the first and second elements.
If you want to have some fun with pairs,
you can chain calls,
the Kotlin compiler will add the parentheses for you.
And you can print the first element of the first element,
or you can add your own parentheses,
and print the equipment.
If we can put together pairs it would be helpful if we could also separate them.
This is called destructuring,
and we do it to take apart an object and assign it to multiple variables,
such as 'val', 'tool',
'use' and assign it to 'fishnet'.
Now, if we print 'tool' and 'use',
'tool' will be the first value in the pair
'fishnet' and 'use' will be the second value 'catching fish'.
There are also triplet's and destructuring components,
and we've added links to the documentation in the notes.
We can turn a pair into a string,
with two string or we can turn it into a list.
So, what is this good for?
Well, you can use it to return more than one values from a function.
You have your function 'return a pair' and destructure it on arrival.
We can make a function 'giveMeATool' that returns a pair of 'fishnet' to 'catching'.
We can destructure it,
and we can print the 'tool' and the 'use'.
Next, let's take a look at collections.