So, there's this classic and wholly overused interview question
where you're given a piece of paper,
or more modern, a laptop,
and asked on the fly to reverse the elements of a list or array.
The code looks something like this in most languages.
You hand the list to a function that loops through the list and a second list,
and adds at the index of the second list the elements of the first list at the size
minus index and always remember the extra minus one to account for the zero with element.
Okay, I'm out of breath.
We can improve on this in Kotlin a bit by using down to to
traverse the list from the end to the beginning instead of from the beginning to the end,
and you's ''get'' to get the element.
But it's still painful and the designers of Kotlin thought so, too.
So, in Kotlin, we can just ask a list for it's reversed version.
Note that the list is not mutable.
Reverse returns a new list.
This is just one example of where the Kotlin designers
made it simple to do stuff that you do all the time,
and that looks the same every time you do it.
But let's get back to aquariums.
Here's a list of symptoms that unhealthy fish can display.
We called mutableListOf, this time.
ListOf gives us a list that we can't change,
but mutableList Of gives us a list that we can change,
which means we'll be able to modify what's in the list.
In Kotlin, it's important to know there's a ListOf and mutableListOf method.
It's good style to prefer ListOf,
but mutableListOf is there when you need it.
Some other predefined functions you can use on lists are Contains,
which tests whether an item is contained in the list,
Sublist creates a sublist from the index that's
the first argument to and excluding the index that's the second argument.
You can do math on lists, for example,
sum which not surprisingly will sum up all the values of the list.
And if our list isn't something that Kotlin knows how to sum,
we can help it out using sumBy.
SumBy takes a lambda that specifies what property of the elements to summarize.
The ''it'' is the default name for lambda arguments and here,
it refers to each element of the list as it's traversed.
There is a lot more.
One way to see all of the available functionality is to create a list in IntelliJ',
then add the dot,
and check out the autocompletion options in the tool tip.
This works for any object.
Mapping is another useful thing.
So, let's introduce it here.
In Kotlin, you can map pretty much anything to anything else using mapOf.
For a simple example,
you could create a map that matches symptoms,
the keys, and diseases of fish, the values.
You can then retrieve the disease value based on the symptom key using ''get'',
or even shorter angle brackets.
One interesting thing is that we can specify what to do if a key, a symptom,
is not found in the list,
and provide a default value,
a default disease with ''get'' or default.
When no value is found for a supplied key,
bloating, the default value is supplied in the second argument.
"Sorry, I don't know" is then returned.
If we need to do more than just return a value,
we can use the getOrElse function.
Instead of returning a simple default value,
whatever code is between the curly braces is executed.
This could be as fancy as, for example,
finding a web page with a cure and returning it.
Just like mutableListOf, you can also make a mutableMapOf.
A mutableMap let's you put and remove items.
Here, we make an inventory map that we can modify.
Then we put three tank scrubbers into the inventory and remove the fish net.
It's pretty easy to remember.
ListOf and mapOf make immutable collections.
That means you can add or remove elements.
MutableListOf and mutableMapOf make collections you can modify.
Immutable collections are particularly useful in
a threaded environment where you might be in
trouble if multiple threads touch the same collection.