Let's talk about constants.
In Kotlin, we can make top level constants and assign
them a value at compile time using const val.
So then we have val and const val,
and what is the difference?
For both we can assign a value directly,
but const val, the value is always determined at compile time.
Well, with val, the value that is assigned can be determined during program execution.
So, for val we can assign the return value from
a function as its value because we can set it during execution.
Const val is set at compile time,
so we cannot call and execute a function to get its value set.
However, const val only works at the top level and in classes
declared with object not with regular classes declared with class.
So, we can use this to create a file or object that
contains only constants and import them one-by-one.
Kotlin does not have a concept of class level constants.
To define constants inside a class,
you have to wrap them into a companion object.
The basic difference between companion objects and regular objects is as follows.
Companion objects are initialized from the static constructor of the containing class,
that is, they are created when the object is created.
Plain objects are initialized lazily on the first access to that object,
that is, when they are first used.
There is more, but all that you need to know is to wrap
constants in classes inside a companion object.