How many times have you written util functions that add
helpful behavior to a class? Probably a lot.
Kotlin provides a convenient syntax for declaring these util functions.
Extension functions.
Extension functions allow you to add functions to
an existing class without having access to its source code.
For example, you could declare them in extensions.kt as part of your package.
Under the hood, extensions do not actually modify the classes they extend.
By defining an extension,
you do not insert new members into the class,
we merely make a new function callable with the dot-notation on variables of this type.
An extension function looks like this.
You specify the classes extended before the dot,
then put the function name.
Inside the extension function,
this is bound to the instance it's called on.
Once you defined an extension function,
it's available as if it were declared on the class.
And that's pretty cool.
Of course, we can make hasSpaces way shorter in Kotlin.
We don't need to explicitly say this,
just like in member functions.
The call will find and implicitly use this.
We also don't need to use braces around the body
since this can be represented as one expression.
Extension functions are a great way to add
helpful functionality to classes you don't own.
You can also use it to separate the core API from helper methods on classes you do own.
If we have an AquariumPlant class with a color and a size,
we can define extension functions for helpers.
For example, this red is a useful function
but it's not really part of the core API of AquariumPlant.
By defining it as an extension function,
we clearly show that it's just a helper.
Note though, extension functions are defined outside of the class they extend.
So, they don't get access to private variables.
If we try to define an isBig function on AquariumPlant,
we'll get an error saying "Size is private."
You should think of them as helper functions that rely only on the public API.
Extension functions are always resolved
statically based on the variable they're applied to.
Let's make a GreenLeafyPlant class that extends AquariumPlant,
then declare two extension functions as free functions outside of the class.
We extend AquariumPlant to print
"AquariumPlant" and GreenLeafyPlant to print "GreenLeafyPlant."
In an example function,
let's make of our plant variable of GreenLeafyPlant.
And now when we print the plant, it prints "GreenLeafyPlant."
In the same function,
let's create another variable,
AquariumPlant of type AquariumPlant,
and use the plant we just created.
We might expect that printing AquariumPlant would print "GreenLeafyPlant." Let's try it.
It turns out when we call prints on AquariumPlant, it prints "AquariumPlant."
This is because the extension function is resolved statically.
That is at compile time.
And the compiler, it just looks at the type of the variable.
So at compile time,
AquariumPlant is an AquariumPlant,
and so it will print "AquariumPlant."
You can define extension properties too.
Just like extension functions,
you specify the class you're extending,
followed by the dot,
followed by the property name.
Here, we're extending AquariumPlant declaring "isGreen."
We define a getter,
where we're checking whether the color is green.
We can use isGreen just like a regular property.
In this example function,
we make a plant and then tests whether it's green.
This calls the getter of isGreen and returns true.
You can also make the class you're extending,
which is sometimes called the receiver nullable.
If you do that, then the "this?"
variable used in the body can be null.
Make sure you test for that.
Let's define a pull method that takes some nullable receiver.
That is the object on which the extension function is called can be null.
We indicate this with a question mark after AquariumPlant,
but before the dot.
Inside the body, we can test for null by using?.apply.
You would want to take a nullable receiver if you expect
the callers will want to call your extension function on nullable variables,
or if you want to provide a default behavior when your function is applied to know.
Extension functions are really powerful,
and most of the Kotlin standard library is implemented as extension function.
Once you've got the hang of them,
you'll find yourself defining them every time you want to
add some extra functionality to a class.