Kotlin like many languages has generic types.
A generic type allows you to make a class generic.
You can think of it like this,
if we wanted to define a list class in Kotlin,
we could make one for each data type.
Here, we're starting to declare a list that can hold integers, N1 for shorts.
Without generics, we need to implement a new copy of list for each type,
another one for double,
one for string and one more for fish.
With generics, we can make the list generic so it can hold any type of object.
It's like you make the type a wildcard that will fit many types.
To do that, we add a generic type to our list.
The generic type is T,
but you can use any letter or even a longer name.
This is just a convention for Type.
You put it inside angle brackets after the class name.
We pronounce this list of T. We can then use T
inside the MyList class as if it was a regular type inside the class.
In this example, the return type for get and the parameter type for
addItem are both T. To use a generic class,
you specify the type you want to use in angle brackets when you instantiate the class.
Here, we are making a MyList of string and MyList of fish.
Because lists are so common,
they are built into Kotlin.
To talk more about generics,
let's add some functionality to our Aquarium.
In this example, we're going to modify
the Aquarium class to support different types of water supplies.
To keep the example simple,
let's create a new package under Aquarium and call it generics.
In the generics package,
create a new Aquarium file.
This allows us to redefine stuff using the same names without conflicts,
so all our code goes into this file.
Files don't have to have the same name as
their class and you can have multiple classes in a file.
To get started, let's make a type hierarchy.
This is stuff we covered in the last lesson,
but here is a review.
WaterSupply is an open class so that we can subclass from it.
It has a var parameter,
needsProcessed that's a Boolean.
The needsProcessed parameter, automatically creates a mutable property on
WaterSupply called needsProcessed along with a getter and setter.
The subclass TapWater extends WaterSupply.
It passes true for needsProcessed because our tap water contains
additives which are bad for fish and thus needs to be processed.
TapWater defines a function called addChemicalCleaners.
After we nominally clean the water,
it sets needsProcessed to false because now we do not need to process the water anymore.
We can set needsProcessed from WaterSupply in here
because it's public by default and so available to child classes.
We create two more subclasses of WaterSupply,
fish store water, and lake water.
Fish store water doesn't need to be processed
so it passes false to the WaterSupply constructor.
Lake water needs to be filtered with filter,
but then it doesn't need to be processed any more.
So, needsProcessed can be false.
I know, that code is very similar to TapWater,
but we'll need it later.
If any of that was a surprise to you,
hop back to the previous lesson and review inheritance in Kotlin.
Now that we have some types to work with,
let's make a generic Aquarium.
We define an Aquarium class,
put T in brackets after the class name.
Now, T is available to the Aquarium class.
We typically say generic types as type T,
that is type followed by the name of the generic.
Now, let's add an immutable property WaterSupply of type T to Aquarium.
Now we can make a new Aquarium and pass it a water supply.
We instantiate Aquarium at angle brackets with the type
right after the class name and then, like normal parentheses.
Since this is an Aquarium of TapWater,
we can pass a TapWater instance as the value for the WaterSupply parameter.
Now, we can access WaterSupply and because it's of type TapWater,
we can go ahead and call addChemicalCleaners,
without doing any casts.
Kotlin does have type inference,
so there's no reason to say TapWater twice when we create the instance.
The type can be inferred by the arguments to Aquarium.
So, if we remove the angle brackets and what's between them,
we'll still make an Aquarium of type TapWater.
Let's try one more example and pass a string to Aquarium.
This doesn't look right.
I'm able to pass a string in as a water supply.
This is because type T doesn't have any bounds.
So, it can actually be set to any type,
that could be a problem.
Another unexpected example is passing in nulls this also works.
I didn't really want to let WaterSupply be null.
Why is Kotlin even letting me pass null as it's of type T,
not T question mark?
Well, it turns out that by default T stands for the nullable any type,
the type at the top of the type hierarchy.
We can change Aquarium in longhand and spell it out as it is like so.
Now, to ensure that our parameter must be nonnull,
but can still be any type,
we remove the question mark and just say any.
This makes it impossible to pass null,
and we now get an error down here,
but we really want to ensure our type is a water supply.
As it turns out,
we can be as specific as we want with
the generic constraint and replace any with the top of any type hierarchy we want to use.
Here we are saying T must be a water supply.
Now, we don't have to worry about someone passing in an oil barrel instead,
which would not be so good for our fish.
We can create a method,
add water in Aquarium that adds water to the tank from the water supply.
There are a few cool things packed into this function.
Check is a standard library function in Kotlin
that's really convenient for checking the state of your classes.
It acts as an assertion and it will throw an illegal exception if its argument is false.
This reads like, if the water supply does not need to be processed,
go on to the next statement.
Otherwise, throw an exception with the provided error message.
You don't need parenthesis because the dot has precedence over the exclamation mark.
Note that we can always access needsProcessed on
WaterSupply because T has a generic constraint of WaterSupply.
We can now make a function that creates an Aquarium using
lake water as to supply and run it and we get an exception.
So, we need to filter the water before we add it, let's do that.
And we can't make an Aquarium of string anymore,
it will give us a compiler error because string is not
a water supply and that's the basics of generics.
There's actually a lot more to generics that we're about to cover,
but this is the most important concept.
How to declare a generic class with an upper bound and use it.