If we take a look at our Aquarium class,
we can see that the generic type is only ever returned by the property water supply.
We didn't define any functions that take a value of type t as a parameter.
Kotlin let's us define out types for exactly this case.
Out types are type parameters that only ever occur in return values of functions,
or on Val properties.
If we try to pass an out type as a parameter to a function,
Kotlin will give us a compiler error.
Once we make a generic type and out type,
Kotlin can infer extra information about where our types are safe to use.
For example, let's declare a function,
addItemTo that expects an aquarium of water supply.
We can call addItemTo on an aquarium of tap water.
Kotlin can ensure that addItemTo won't do anything unsafe with a generic,
because it's declared as an out type.
If we made the type t not be an out type,
we see that Kotlin gives us a compiler error when calling addItemTo.
Kotlin does this because it can't ensure we're using it safely.
In types are from the same school as out types.
In types can be used anytime the generic is only used as an argument to functions.
More specifically, in types can only be passed into an object.
Out types can only be passed out of an object or returned.
There's one special time you can pass an out type.
Constructors can take out types as arguments,
but functions never can.
The compiler will enforce this.
If we try to return an in type, we'll get an error.
As an example, honestly a bit contrived,
let's say we wanted to make
an interface cleaner that let's us clean different water supplies.
We'll give cleaner a generic t that's a water supply,
and since we're only ever using t as an argument to clean,
we can make it an in type.
To use the cleaner interface,
we'll make a class tap water cleaner that
implements cleaner for cleaning tap water by adding chemicals.
Now, in our Aquarium class,
we can update add water to take a cleaner of type T,
and we can now clean the water before we add it.
Kotlin will figure out what this means,
and make sure your generics usage is safe.
Now, when a water supply needs processed,
we can use cleaner to clean it.
Finally, we can use our aquarium like this,
make a new tap water cleaner,
then make a new aquarium of tap water.
When we call add water,
we'll pass the cleaner to add water.
Out and in are really easy to remember.
Out types can be used as return values,
and in types can be used as parameters.
The IDE will suggest you add out or in to your generic types when it's correct to do so.
So, if you forget,
look for the warning to add out and in.
If you want to dig into the sort of problems that they solve,
the documentation covers them in depth.