Sometimes, we want to make a generic function.
Typically, this is a really good idea whenever
the function takes an argument of a class that has a generic.
Let's make a function isWaterClean.
It takes an aquarium and we need to specify the generic type of the parameter.
One option is to use water supply,
but this means aquarium must have an out type parameter for this to be called.
What can we do to make this better?
We can make the function generic.
You can add a generic to a function by
putting angle brackets right after the keyword, "fun".
Here, we're saying isWaterCleaner is a function with a generic argument, "T".
T is constrained by water supply.
Once we have the type T,
we can use as the generic to aquarium.
Another way to say that is,
T is a type parameter to isWaterClean that is
being used to specify the generic type of the aquarium.
This pattern is really common,
and it's a good idea to take a moment to work through this.
We can call this function by specifying the type in
angle brackets right after the function name and before the parenthesis.
And because of type inference,
we don't need to explicitly use the angle brackets.
The compiler figures it out from the type aquarium.
You can use generic functions for methods too,
even in classes that have their own generic type.
Let's add one to aquarium that let's us check if it has a type of water supply.
Here, we're declaring a function hasWaterSupply of type that has
a generic parameter R. R is bound by WaterSupply.
In the body, we're going to return "true" if
the water supply parameter is of type R. Remember,
WaterSupply is of type T,
and this is really saying return true if T is
R. We have to do one more thing to make this function work.
In order to use R in isCheck like this,
we have to tell Kotlin that it's reified.
Reified just means real.
A reified type is a real type.
To make a type reified,
use the keyword "inline" before "fun" and the keyword
"reified" before R. When we do that,
we're saying, declare a type parameter R,
but make it a real type.
Kotlin does this by inlining the function to the call.
Anytime you call this function,
it will automatically be dropped in place of the call.
The compiler then figures out what type R would have been and uses the real type.
Once a type is a reified or real,
you can use it just like a normal type.
That's because it is a real type after inlining.
That means, you can do isChecks using the type.
If you don't use reified here,
the type won't be real enough for Kotlin to allow isChecks,
and that's because non reified types are only available at compile time,
but can't be used at runtime by your program.
Just like calling generic functions,
call generic methods by using angle brackets after the function name.
Here we're saying, call "hasWaterSupplyOfType" on aquarium.
Pass TapWater as the type parameter for R. Of course,
this returns true since our aquarium does have TapWater.
We can use reified types for regular functions too,
not just members and even extension functions.
Here, we're defining an extension function on water supply called, isTypeOf.
It has a reified or real type T. Just like hasWaterSupplyOfType,
we'll do an isCheck to use the reified type.
Sometimes, when we take a generic class as an argument,
we don't actually care what its generic type is.
We can use star protection to say,
"I'll take any version of that generic type."
Let's move hasWaterSupplyOfType to be an extension function.
It isn't really part of the core API of aquarium,
so, it makes sense.
We don't really care what type of aquarium hasWaterSupplyOfType is called on.
So, we can say that simply by putting an asterisk or star as the generic.
This says, I'll take any aquarium no matter what the generic type is.
This is a convenient way to skip specifying a type when you don't really need to care.
Kotlin will make sure you don't do anything unsafe too.
In and out, generic functions reified, types, star projections.
Only one more topic,
then you'll know everything there is to know about Kotlin generics.
Type erasure. It'll come up in some error messages that the compiler produces,
so, it's worth learning about.
All generic types are only used at compile time by Kotlin.
This let's the compiler makes sure that you're doing everything safely.
However, at runtime, all the generic types are erased.
It turns out, the compiler can create
completely correct code without keeping the generic types to runtime,
but it does mean that sometimes you do something like
isChecks on a generic type that the compiler can't support.
That's why Kotlin added reified or real types.
And now, you really do know everything there is to know about Kotlin generics.