Annotations are a means of attaching metadata to code.
That is, the annotations are read by the compiler,
and used to generate code or even logic.
Annotations are not Kotlin specific,
but Kotlin offers some useful annotations.
Annotations go right before the thing that is annotated,
and most things can be annotated: classes,
functions, methods, and even control structures.
Some annotations can even take arguments.
There are annotations that are available through
the Kotlin standard library that control the way code is compiled.
They're really useful if you're exporting Kotlin to Java,
but otherwise you don't need them that often.
Here, we're saying that the exported name of this file is
InteropFish with the JvmName annotation.
The JvmName annotation is taking an argument of InteropFish.
Then in the companion object by saying JvmStatic,
we tell Kotlin to make the Interop function a static function on InteropFish.
We need to use a companion object because we're making the function static.
Many frameworks use annotations to configure how they run.
You can even create your own annotations.
Let's say you have a simple plant class with two methods.
You can then use reflection to get information about the class at runtime,
that's the colon, colon class operation.
This is useful, and let's Kotlin look into the properties on classes, or reflect.
Here, we're just printing all of the methods on the class.
It'll print trim and fertilize.
Here's the most basic annotation.
It doesn't do anything other than tell you it's annotated.
This is the complete annotation even if all it does is exist,
and you use it like this.
You can get all of the annotations of a class,
and do something in response such as print them,
and you can check for a specific annotation and do something in response.
One important thing to know because it comes up a lot when using frameworks,
annotations can target getters or setters.
When they do, you can apply them with the get colon,
or set colon prefix.
Let's declare two annotations.
OnGet can only be applied to property getters,
OnSet can only be applied to property setters.
Here I'm saying, apply OnGet to isGrowing's getter,
and apply OnSet to needsFood setter.
That's all we're going to cover for annotations.
They're really powerful for creating libraries that inspect
annotations both at runtime and sometimes at compile time.
However, typical application code just uses annotations provided by frameworks.