Kotlin has several ways of controlling flow.
You are already familiar with return which
returns from a function to its enclosing function.
Break is like return but for loops.
Kotlin gives you additional control over loops with what's called a labeled break.
A break qualified with a label jumps to
the execution point right after the loop marked with that label.
What happens since this function is that if I is greater than 10,
we break and resume execution at the label.
What this does is give you better control over nested loops.
Any expression in Kotlin may be marked with a label.
Labels have the form of an identifier followed by the add sign.
Check the grammar for more information on this.
To label an expression,
we just put a label in front of it.