All right, we have an aquarium and decorations
and equipment and we can take pretty good care of our fish by now.
There is just one important thing missing, the fish.
It's the fish that we went through all this trouble for.
Everything else, while useful and beautiful and fascinating, it's scaffolding.
Our course so far is a little bit like this.
Everything we learned is fundamental to writing good Kotlin code,
but we think that the fish of Kotlin are its functional features.
The ability to multiply, change using extensions,
which we've already covered,
higher order functions, and lambdas.
So, we'll see you in the final lesson where there will be lots of fish.