Welcome back. In this lesson,
you're going to use the Kotlin interpreter
to get comfortable with the basic language features.
It is best if you just follow along with us,
as we type out and explain the examples.
To make this a bit more entertaining,
we will go at a good pace,
and we're going to wrap all of this into an aquarium.
Now, I've had aquarium since my aunt gave me one.
Plants and all when I was about nine.
There's everything in an aquarium,
to teach your Kotlin.
Now, we couldn't really set up a big fancy aquarium here at the studio.
But, we hope you enjoy our small project.
I'm not really sure how Kotlin is like an aquarium,
but I bet we'll all find out by the end of this course.
Let's get started with the basics.