So, for this screencast,
I'm going to type the code into the interpreter and you can see
exactly what it does and then I'll explain it as we go.
We'll start intelliJ.
Type along if you want and pause the video if you get out of breath.
Or, you can just wait and watch,
and then practice in the practice section.
You don't have to memorize all of this on the go
because at the end we'll give you a Kotlin cheat sheet.
So first, let's get operators out of the way,
plus, minus, times and division.
In your typewriter, type
one plus one command enter for one fish plus fun fish to the aquarium.
And you get 53 fish.
Sadly, three of the baby fish are eaten by sharks.
Because the fish keep fighting over food,
you want to divide the fish into batches of 10.
Dividing an integer always returns an integer.
So, one divided by two return zero,
and 1.0 divided by 2.0 returns to 0.5.
But your fish keep multiplying and after six months you have a lot of fish.
We'll cover it a bit later,
but Kotlin let's you override the basic operators.
You're not just stuck adding one's and two's.
You can define your own fish,
and give them the ability to multiply.
Another edition about addition,
Kotlin keeps numbers as primitives,
the same number types your CPU uses.
But, it'll let you call methods on them like they're objects.
This means you can call methods on the number one like one times two.
There's a few things to note about basic types.
While you can use numbers as if they were objects,
Kotlin also supports object wrappers for numbers.
All the numerical types in Kotlin have a supertype called number.
And if you try to store the value one in a variable of type number,
it'll need to be placed in an object wrapper,
this is called boxing.
And it will be implicitly done whenever it is needed in your program.
Importantly, as a developer,
you can avoid creating these objects wrappers by not storing numbers in objects.
To write useful code you need to be able to store values.
To make your fish more permanent,
you can store them in variables.
There are two types of variables in Kotlin; changeable and unchangeable.
With val, you can assign a value once.
If you try to assign something again, you get an error.
With var you can assign a value,
and then you can change it.
Note that in all of these the type is inferred,
which means the compiler can figure out the type from the context.
Even so the type is inferred,
it becomes fixed at compile time,
and you can not change the type of a variable in
Kotlin once it's type has been determined.
Of course, you can use variables in operations and there is no punctuation at the end.
On the topic of implicit.
Number types won't implicitly convert to other types so you can't assign
a short value to a long variable or a byte to an int.
Kotlin does this because
implicit numerical conversion is a common source of errors in programs.
You can always assign them by casting like this.
You may have seen syntax like this before,
Kotlin supports underscores in numbers.
So you can specify long constants in a format that makes sense to you.
The type is inferred by Kotlin.
Okay. Let's do something that's really Kotlin.
Nullability. Earlier, we talked about how Kotlin helps avoid null pointer exceptions.
When you declare a variables type explicitly,
by default, it's value can not be null.
Use the question mark operator to indicate that a variable can be null.
When you have complex data types such as a list,
you can allow for the list to be null,
but if it's not null,
it's elements cannot be null,
or you can allow both the list or the elements to be null.
If you really love no pointer exceptions,
Kotlin will let you keep them.
The not know assertion operator can force your way past a nullable type in Kotlin.
Though, it will still throw an exception when it's null.
In programming slang, the exclamation mark is often called, Bang.
See the Wikipedia article in the notes.
It's a lot easier to say double bang then not null whatever.
It's generally a bad idea to use the double bang operator and
that's why they've made you type two exclamation marks instead of one.
You can do some cool null testing with the question mark operator,
saving you the pain of many if else statements.
For example, you can check whether an object or
variable is non null before accessing one of its methods.
You can and will only give fish treats if they are tweets available.
You can also chain null tests in an expression,
like this return statement,
if fish food treats is not null,
use a treat and return a new value and otherwise,
return the value after the colon, which is zero.
So, in this expression,
we are checking whether fish fruit treats is null.
If it is not, we remove a treat and return a new value.
If fish food treats is null,
we stop evaluation, so that the decrease method is not called on a null object.
And we return the alternative value after the colon,
which in this case is zero.
Look at the question mark colon operator.
It's called the Elvis operator,
because it's like a smiley on its side with the way Elvis Presley style his hair.