Of course, we have strings in Kotlin,
and they were pretty much like strings in any other language.
You can concatenate strings using plus,
but even better you can use string templates to
build strings by combining them with values.
The dollar variable name is replaced by text representing its value.
And as a preview of things to come,
you can also do this.
The two numbers get added first,
and the result is printed.
Like other languages, Kotlin has a Boolean data type and operators.
Two equal sign equals a by value comparison,
and of course, you have not equal, greater,
smaller or equal operators just like in other languages.
Now that we can get to the truth of matters,
we can test for conditions.
The two basic ones in Kotlin are if-else and when.
If-else is for comparing values.
Equal Kotlin thing is that you can be more flexible about
your conditions by using ranges, like so.
We'll see more ranges in a moment,
and when, which is Kotlin's way of doing switching.
You can of course nest ifs and whens to your heart's delight,
and again, you can use ranges.