Now, here's the thing about val.
If your val variable value is a reference,
then you cannot assign it a different reference later.
But if you're referencing something that's not immutable,
it can still change.
Val only applies to the reference,
and it doesn't make the object it points to immutable.
In this example, we cannot assign a different list in my list,
but we can manipulate the elements of the lists,
such as removing an element.
Now for loops, we need something to loop over.
So, here are lists and arrays as examples of collections.
Arrays work pretty much as you'd expect with some cool additions.
You can create an array with arrayOf.
You can create typed arrays,
for example integers, but if you add another type element it gives you an error.
But you can mix types in untyped arrays.
To print the array,
you can convert its contents to a string with toString.
You'll probably see an error in the interpreter.
Wait for the tool tip,
and then press options enter to import arrays from the standard library.
You can nest arrays.
When you put an array within an array,
you have an array of arrays,
not a flattened array of the contents of the two.
A really cool feature of arrays in Kotlin is
the ability to initialize them with dynamic code.
Don't worry too much about the syntax for now.
The important point is to see how much boilerplate code this cut-out.
You can read this as initialize an array of five elements,
assign each item to its index times two.
Once you have arrays,
you want to do something with their elements and that often happens in a for loop.
Here is your basic loop over an array.
Here are a few other things you can do with for loops.
You can loop over the index along with the elements,
which saves you from having to use
the index to get the element inside the body of the loop.
It's much more readable this way.
You've seen ranges and here is more.
You can do ranges in an alphabet.
You can do ranges of numbers.
You can do a range going downwards,
and you can do a range advancing in multiple steps.