There are a few steps to get a project setup.
If you don't already have a JDK,
or Java Development Kit installed,
take a moment to install a JDK before you start IntelliJ.
When you first start an IntelliJ,
you'll have to click through a setup wizard.
The default options are mostly spot on.
I prefer dark blue theme,
but choose the option that you prefer.
After you run through the setup wizard,
you'll be presented with a welcome screen like this.
We'll need to create a Kotlin project,
so IntelliJ knows that we're working in Kotlin.
To do that, create a project,
select Kotlin in the left-hand navigation,
select Kotlin/JVM in the right panel,
name your project "Hello Kotlin," click Finish.
When you're done, you'll have created a project set up to run Kotlin.
Now that you're in a project,
you can access the Kotlin REPL or read-eval-print loop.
In contrast to the compiler,
a REPL evaluates the code you're typing in right after you hit Command Enter.
You'll find it in Tools, Kotlin, REPL.
In good tradition, we start with Hello World.
Type or paste the following printHello function code into
the REPL and press Control Enter or Command Enter under Mac.
The code is also in the notes below the video.
To execute the code,
type printHello, and Control or Command Enter.
Do you see the result? There you have it.
You have just written and executed
your first piece of Kotlin code. Let's take a look at it.
The fun keyword designates a function followed by the name of the function right here.
This is followed by a set of parenthesis where the arguments go.
This function doesn't have any arguments.
Next, we have the curly braces and they frame the function body.
Inside a function, we can make calls.
This call is for println,
which prints one line of text.
We are printing the string, "Hello World".
You do not have to specify a return type because we're not returning anything in
this function and you may notice that there
is no punctuation at the end of your statements.
No semicolons.